<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ifcuriousthenlearn (Posts about software)</title><link>https://nagordon.github.io/ifcuriousthenlearn/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://nagordon.github.io/ifcuriousthenlearn/categories/software.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;neal&lt;/a&gt; copyright Neal Gordon</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:14:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Windows package management with Chocolatey</title><link>https://nagordon.github.io/ifcuriousthenlearn/blog/windows-chocolatey/</link><dc:creator>neal</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most of us, using software is an everyday activity. Many of us use lots of different packages of software, especially those that does not come pre-installed, like notepad++, chrome or firefox, ebook managers, your favorite video player, etc. Installing that software every time you get a new computer or keeping all those packages up-to-date can be a challenge. Being a Windows user for most of my life, I've accepted the tedious, risky business of finding, installing and not getting viruses from Windows software. Not until I started using Linux did I realize that it can be easier and safer. Linux uses package management, that changes from distribution, but the popular Debian based Linux uses &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; to install software from the command line. Installing software can be as easy as &lt;code&gt;apt-get install firefox&lt;/code&gt;, and updating all software on the computing can be done with &lt;code&gt;apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;. Really easy right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I still use Windows a lot, and installating and managing software on Windows can be be much easier using &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/choco/wiki"&gt;chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;. Chocolatey is a Windows command line tool to manage software, including searching, installing, updataing and removing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation is a cinch. Copy and paste this code into a windows command line access by searching for &lt;code&gt;cmd&lt;/code&gt; in the windows start. If possible, run as administrator (cmd, right-click, run as administrator)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;powershell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;NoProfile&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ExecutionPolicy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Bypass&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"iex ((new-object net.webclient).DownloadString('https://chocolatey.org/install.ps1'))"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SET&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ALLUSERSPROFILE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;\&lt;span class="n"&gt;chocolatey&lt;/span&gt;\&lt;span class="n"&gt;bin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I typically just search the chocolatey website for the package I want to install and type that into the command line. The example I want to share is my favorite ebook manager, calibre. One of the reasons I enjoy chocolatey with calibre is because calibre is updated a lot, and to keep up with them, you have to go download the calibre exe, and follow the prompts for the installation. Or a simple command will do it all! The &lt;code&gt;-y&lt;/code&gt; is a flag to indicate &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt; to eliminate the need to confirm the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install calibre -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Updating calibre is as easy as this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco update calibre -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Multiple packages can be installed by leaving a space between the names&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install notepadplusplus googlechrome atom 7zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And to update all the packages that were install with chocolatey, this command will take care of it all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco upgrade all -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think chocolatey is a really neat, useful package that has saved me a lot of time, and I hope it helps alleviate some of your windows woes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;

</description><category>software</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://nagordon.github.io/ifcuriousthenlearn/blog/windows-chocolatey/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>